Zheng (Thomas) Tang

RESEARCH SCIENTIST · EXPERT IN COMPUTER VISION AND MACHINE LEARNING

Amazon - Coral (SEA68), 2201 6th Ave, Seattle, WA 98121, USA

🛮 (+1) 206-669-5590 | 🔀 tangzhengthomas@gmail.com | 🏶 zhengthomastang.github.io | 🖸 zhengthomastang | 🗖 zhengthomastang

Summary .

Current Research Scientist at Amazon · Ph.D. in Electrical & Computer Engineering at the University of Washington (Advisor: Prof. Jenq-Neng Hwang) · Research interests in computer vision and machine learning · 9-month internship at NVIDIA working on city-scale vehicle tracking and ReID with papers accepted to CVPR'19 and ICCV'19 · Leader of the winning team at the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18 · Organizing committee member of the 4th AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'20 · 2 finalist best student paper awards in ICPR'16

Education

University of Washington (UW)

Seattle, WA, USA

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL & COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2019

- · Advised by Prof. Jeng-Neng Hwang (IEEE Fellow) at the Information Processing Lab
- Dissertation topic: Robust Video Object Tracking via Camera Self-Calibration

University of Washington (UW)

Seattle, WA, USA

M.S. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

• GPA: 3.83/4.0

Sep. 2014 - Mar. 2016

Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications (BUPT)

Beijing, China

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

• GPA: 88.73/100

Queen Mary University of London (QMUL)

London, UK

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

· First Class Honours

Work Experience

Amazon.com Seattle, WA, USA

RESEARCH SCIENTIST

Jul. 2019 - PRESENT

Working on a new project at the Amazon Physical Stores Tech Team

NVIDIA Santa Clara, CA, USA

INTELLIGENT VIDEO ANALYTICS INTERN

Jun. 2018 - Mar. 2019

- Created CityFlow, a city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera (MTMC) vehicle tracking and ReID, accepted at CVPR'19 (Oral)
- Proposed PAMTRI, a pose-aware multi-task network for vehicle ReID using highly randomized synthetic data, accepted at ICCV'19
- Supported the 3rd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'19 that attracted 334 academic and industrial research teams from 44 countries
- · Joined the organizing committee of the 4th AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'20, in charge of the MTMC tracking and ReID tracks

University of Washington Seattle, WA, USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Dec. 2014 - Jun. 2018

- Developed evolutionary camera calibration and clustering-based data association for vehicle tracking using fusion of visual and semantic features that achieved rank #1 in Track 1 (Traffic Flow Analysis) of the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18
- Designed multi-camera tracking based on fusion of adaptive appearance models, CNN features and license plate information that achieved rank #1 in Track 3 (Multi-camera Vehicle Detection & ReID) of the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18
- Proposed multi-kernel vehicle tracking based on 3D deformable models that outperformed the state-of-the-art object tracking methods, selected as the winning method of **Track 2 (AI City Applications)** at the **1st AI City Challenge Workshop** in **SmartWorld'17**
- Developed a 3D human pose estimator to enable overlaying AR for medical simulation under 6-DoF camera motion, where a two-step evolutionary pose optimization for camera and humans (2EPOCH) is proposed (funded by ArchieMD Inc.)
- Implemented multi-view 3D tracking of soccer players and the ball that enabled real-time soccer analytics (funded by a startup company)
- Developed single-camera people tracking that is robust against occlusion and cluttered background to provide useful features for object ReID across multiple cameras (funded by Madrona Venture Group)

Prism Skylabs San Francisco, CA, USA

ENGINEERING INTERN

Jul. 2015 - Aug. 2015

- Developed adaptive segmentation and tracking based on multi-kernel feedback that achieved top single-camera tracking accuracy (74.82%)
 on the NLPR_MCT benchmark
- Developed evolutionary camera self-calibration from tracking of humans to automatically back project 2D trajectories into 3D, which received
 2 Finalist Best Student Paper Awards in ICPR'16

Teaching Experience

University of Washington

TEACHING ASSISTANT OF EE 508: STOCHASTIC PROCESSES IN ENGINEERING

Seattle, WA, USA Mar. 2019 - Jun. 2019

Designed topics for final projects, provided tutorials on hidden Markov model and held weekly office hours

Publications

JOURNAL ARTICLES

MOANA: An online learned adaptive appearance model for robust multiple object tracking in 3D

Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang

IEEE Access 7.1 (2019) pp. 31934-31945. 2019

ESTHER: Joint camera self-calibration and automatic radial distortion correction from tracking of walking humans

Zheng Tang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Kuan-Hui Lee, Jenq-Neng Hwang

IEEE Access 7.1 (2019) pp. 10754-10766. 2019

Online-learning-based human tracking across non-overlapping cameras

Young-Gun Lee, Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang

TCSVT 28.10 (2018) pp. 2870-2883. 2018

CONFERENCE PAPERS

The 4th AI City Challenge

Milind Naphade, Shuo Wang, David C. Anastasiu, Zheng Tang, Ming-Ching Chang, Xiaodong Yang, Liang Zheng, Anuj Sharma, Rama Chellappa, Pranamesh Chakraborty

Proc. CVPR Workshops, 2020, Virtual

PAMTRI: Pose-aware multi-task learning for vehicle re-identification using highly randomized synthetic data

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Stan Birchfield, Jonathan Tremblay, William Hodge, Ratnesh Kumar, Shuo Wang, Xiaodong Yang Proc. ICCV, pp. 211-220, 2019, Seoul, Korea

CityFlow: A city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera vehicle tracking and re-identification

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Ming-Yu Liu, Xiaodong Yang, Stan Birchfield, Shuo Wang, Ratnesh Kumar, David Anastasiu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR, pp. 8797-8806, 2019, Long Beach, CA, USA

Joint multi-view people tracking and pose estimation for 3D scene reconstruction

Zheng Tang, Renshu Gu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. ICME, pp. 1-6, 2018, San Diego, CA, USA

Single-camera and inter-camera vehicle tracking and 3D speed estimation based on fusion of visual and semantic features

Zheng Tang, Gaoang Wang, Hao Xiao, Aotian Zheng, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR Workshops, pp. 108-115, 2018, Salt Lake City, UT, USA

Inter-camera tracking based on fully unsupervised online learning

Young-Gun Lee, Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Zhijun Fang

Proc. ICIP, pp. 2607-2611, 2017, Beijing, China

Multiple-kernel adaptive segmentation and tracking (MAST) for robust object tracking

Zheng Tang, Jeng-Neng Hwang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Jen-Hui Chuang

Proc. ICASSP, pp. 1115-1119, 2016, Shanghai, China

Camera self-calibration from tracking of moving persons

Zheng Tang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Kuan-Hui Lee, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Jen-Hui Chuang, Zhijun Fang

Proc. ICPR, pp. 260-265, 2016, Cancún, México

Honors & Awards

2018 Winner of Track 1 (Traffic Flow Analysis), 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18

2018 Winner of Track 3 (Multi-camera Vehicle Detection & ReID), 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18

Salt Lake City, UT, USA San Francisco, CA, USA

Salt Lake City, UT, USA

2017 Winner of Track 2 (AI City Applications), 1st AI City Challenge Workshop in SmartWorld'17

Cancún, México

Seattle, WA, USA

2016 Finalist IBM Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16 2016 Finalist Intel Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16

Cancún, México

Skills

Programming C/C++ (expert), Python (expert), Java (proficient), MATLAB (expert), JavaScript (proficient), MFX(expert)

Frameworks & Tools PyTorch (expert), TensorFlow (expert), MXNet (proficient), Caffe (proficient), Git (expert), React (proficient)

English (proficient), Mandarin (native), Cantonese (native), Spanish (elementary)